<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nhat Duy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nhat Duy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Firebase: Push notification in iOS</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/google-firebase-push-notification-in-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/google-firebase-push-notification-in-ios/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction Push Notifications is a loud and powerful way for our apps to engage with our users. We engage with our users by letting them see values with their very owns eyes. Users see values. Users engage. We can engage our users by letting them know about something important. Perhaps their favorite sport team is about to compete. A flash sale on watermelons is on for 30 minutes. Or there is an important meet up in the desert later this weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Developer Center and App Store Connect</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/apple-developer-center-and-app-store-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/apple-developer-center-and-app-store-connect/</guid>
      <description>1. General First you create an AppleID. You then use that AppleID to register for a Developer program. Registering to a developer program gives access to two types of accounts. Or rather say that you are provided with the access to two different portals for the same account. One is Developer Program portal and another is App Store Connect portal.
1. Apple Developer Center (Developer Program) 2. App Store Connect Apple change the name iTune Connect to App Store Connect since 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple keys and certificates</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/apple-keys-and-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/apple-keys-and-certificates/</guid>
      <description>1. Apple Development This file is used to added to Xcode, then developer can run app on device.
1. Mobile provision keys (.mobileprovision file) It is created from Apple Developer Center. Go to Profiles -&amp;gt; Select plus button -&amp;gt; Select iOS App Development (Create a provisioning profile&amp;hellip;) -&amp;gt; Select App ID which created from a -&amp;gt; In Select Certificate and Select Devices, select all -&amp;gt; Download .mobileprovision file 2. Certificate Signing Request (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a custom view in iOS: Everything needs to know</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/create-a-custom-view-in-ios-everything-needs-to-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/create-a-custom-view-in-ios-everything-needs-to-know/</guid>
      <description>1. Introduction In iOS programming, we usually need to create custom views. We create them not only for reused, in some cases it also help us move a lot of code to other class. In this article, I will share you guys everything we need to know when we create a custom view. What is difference between when we create with nib file and without it. OK, let go&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency in iOS part 4 - Three problems</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-4-three-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-4-three-problems/</guid>
      <description>This article is final part of serial concurrency tutorial, if you have not read part 1, part 2 and part 3, I recommend you read them first.
In this article, I will show you 3 problems that you must pay attention when you use concurrency. Those are race conditions, deadlock and priority inversion.
Let&amp;rsquo;s go&amp;hellip;
1. Race conditions Example you have two threads executing, they are both trying to modify an object&amp;rsquo;s count variable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency in iOS part 3 - GCD and NSOperation</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-3-gcd-nsoperation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-3-gcd-nsoperation/</guid>
      <description>This article is part 3 of serial concurrency tutorial, if you have not read part 1 and part 2, I recommend you read them first.
In this article, I will show you GCD and NSOperation. Advantages and disadvantages of them.
Common&amp;hellip;
1. Grand Central Dispatch (GCD) GCD is lowest level to support run the tasks concurrently. It is easy for impletation. Basically, we use GCD in most cases.
There are 3 kinds of queue in GCD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency in iOS part 2 - Serial and concurrent queue</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-2-serial-and-concurrent-queue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-2-serial-and-concurrent-queue/</guid>
      <description>This article is part 2 of serial concurrency tutorial, if you have not read part 1, I recommend you read it first.
In this article, I will show you serial queue and concurrent queue. However, before we move on to them, we also need to know about synchronous and asynchronous.
1. Synchronous and asynchronous The tasks may either perform synchronous or asynchronous.
When the task is running as synchronous, your app will wait and lock current run loop until the task finishes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency in iOS part 1 - Introduction to CPU, process and thread</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-1-introduction-to-cpu-process-and-thread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/concurrency-in-ios-part-1-introduction-to-cpu-process-and-thread/</guid>
      <description>Before we learn deeply about concurrency in iOS, I will briefly show you the basic related knowledge. That are CPU, process and thread.
1. What is the CPU used in iPhone? Apple used many different CPU for their phone.
Example:
iPhone 6, 6S used dual core
iPhone 7, 7S used 4-core
iphone 8, 8S used 6-core
iPhone XS, XS Max, XR used 8-core
2. What is process? To meet the demand running many applications at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>