<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>business on Nhat Duy&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/tags/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in business on Nhat Duy&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nhatduy129.github.io/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The best real estate I ever received</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/the-best-real-estate-i-ever-received/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/the-best-real-estate-i-ever-received/</guid>
      <description>1. Notes Real estate is all about wasting time. The more time you waste, the more money you can take. (p. 4)
Always develop on the area growth is comming. If you are a little early, the growth will bail you out. If you develop on an area that the growth is already done or it not continuing, if you are wrong, you are wrong forever. (p. 18)
Auction helps both seller and buyer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Một đời quản trị</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/mot-doi-quan-tri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/mot-doi-quan-tri/</guid>
      <description>1. Notes Mỗi khi nhân viên than thiếu người, Phan Văn Trường chọn cách cắt giảm nhân sự. Vì ông tin rằng, team đông người quá mức cần thiết cho nên dẫn tới việc thiếu đoàn kết, nên làm việc kém hiệu quả, công việc bị đình trệ. Khi nhân sự cắt giảm đi thì team gắn bó hơn, mọi người tranh nhau làm việc.
Người lớn với trẻ con cũng ko khác nhau là mấy, chỉ khác nhau ở việc dấu giếm, che đậy bản chất tính cách của mình.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tứ thư lãnh đạo</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/tu-thu-lanh-dao/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/tu-thu-lanh-dao/</guid>
      <description>1. Notes Những thứ tác động nhanh ko nguy hiểm, tác động từ từ mới nguy hiểm. Câu chuyện chú ếch và hiệu ứng cá da trơn. (p. 139)
Không dành nhiều thời gian để dự đoán tương lai, vì như vậy dễ làm bỏ lỡ thời cơ đưa ra quyết sách. Chuyên gia kinh tế học cũng có những dự đoán sai lệch.
Phải giữ uy tín.
Phải biết nắm bắt cơ hội.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to talk to anyone</title>
      <link>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/how-to-talk-to-any-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nhatduy129.github.io/post/books/how-to-talk-to-any-one/</guid>
      <description>1. Notes How to win friends and influence people is old one, for 21st century, we need new techneque.
Smile slowly, the way we smile is very important.
Big winners have 50 vocabularies more than others, try to use as many as vocabulary as possible
Try to get quoted from books, internet, use them when you get in the talk show.
Never ever make a joke at anyone elses expense.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>